Guide to the Printmaker File [1730]-2014, undated (bulk 1800-1860) PR 58
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Prints 16 x 20" and smaller
  - Plowman, George T. (1869-1932)
    - Lefferts Homestead (3/50), undated (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - Wyckoff Homestead, Brooklyn, N.Y. (3/50), undated (Offsite-box P, Box P)
  - Prang, Louis (1824-1909)
    Includes lithographs after Winslow Homer, from Campaign Sketches, 1863
    - "The Letter for Home" (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - "Foraging" (Offsite-box P, Box P)
    - "Our Jolly Cook" (Offsite-box P, Box P)
  - Price, Chester B. (1885-1962)
    - Manhattan Forum, undated (Offsite-box P, Box P)
  - Quinlan, Will J. (1877-1919)
    - Fulton Street, 1923 (Offsite-box Q-R, Box Q)
  - Raskin, Joseph (1897-1981)
    - "Amherst College", undated (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R)
    - "Blair Hall, Princeton University", undated (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R)
    - "Campbell Hall, Princeton University", undated (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R)
    - "The Chapel, Amherst College", undated (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - "Chapin Hall, Williams College", undated (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - "The Converse Hall, Amherst College", undated (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - "Griffin Hall, Williams College", undated (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - "Memorial Hall, Harvard University", undated (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - "Princeton University", undated (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - "The Rotunda," University of Virginia", undated (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - "Serpentine Wall, University of Virginia", undated (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - "Sever Hall, Harvard University", undated (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - "West College, Williams College", undated (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - "West Lawn, University of Virginia", undated (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - "Widener Library, Harvard University", undated (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
  - Reid, Andrew
    - Grand Central, undated (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
  - Reisman, Philip (1904-1992)
    - Builders I (60/100), 1928 (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - Builders II (99/100), 1928 (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - Fruit Wagon (23/100), 1929 (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - The Knife Grinder (38/100), 1929 (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - The Meeting (27/100), 1930 (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - Moving Day (26/100), 1929 (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - Neighborhood Park (33/100), 1929 (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - Peddler (34/100), 1928 (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - Peddlers Under the 'L' (37/100), 1928 (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - Pershing Square (75/100), undated (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - Soda Fountain (42/100), 1928 (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - Veterans - World War I (40/100), 1931 (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
  - Revere, Paul (1735-1818)
    - "The Bloody Massacre Perpetrated in King Street Boston on March 5th 1770...," (Offsite-box Revere, Folder unknown container)
      hand-colored engraving
  - Roth, Ernest D. (1879-1964)
    - Coenties Slip, N.Y., 1935 (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - "The South Side of the Inn at Buck Hill Falls", 1940 (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
      published by Buck Hill Art Association
  - Ruzicka, Rudolph (1883-1978)
    - [St. John's Chapel, 40 Varick St.] (33/75), 1911 (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
    - [Clapboard house overlooking river], [1909] (Offsite-box Q-R, Box R, Folder unknown container)
  - Sabin, Joseph F. (1846-1926)
    - [New York Produce Exchange from Castle Garden], ca. 1895 (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
  - Sartain, John (1808-1897)
    - "Common Deer", 1830 (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
      hand-colored line engraving after Thomas Doughty (1793-1856). Plate One from The Cabinet of Natural History and American Rural Sports: with Illustrations (Philadelphia: J & T. Doughty, 1830.)
  - Schmidt, Louis
    - Mountains [Hanover Square], 1929 (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
  - Schumann, Karl
    - Temples Old and New, undated (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
  - Schutz, Anton (1894-1977)
    - [East River Bridges], undated (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
    - 544 Hotel Waldorf Astoria, undated (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
    - George Washington Bridge (96/100), undated (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
    - Madison Square, undated (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
  - Shaner?, W.
    - [Dewey Arch], undated (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
  - Sharp, William (1900-1961)
    - Spanish Quarter, New York (5/50), undated (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
    - Third Avenue Nocturne, undated (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
  - Shaw, Robert (1859-1912)
    - Fraunces Tavern, New York, printed for members of the Colonial Society of America, [1906] (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
  - Smith, Wuanita (1866-1959)
    - Columbus Jewels, undated (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
  - Soyer, Raphael (1899-1987)
    - The Artist's Parents, ca. 1963 (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
  - Steeden, O.
    Includes plates from Illustrations to Knickerbocker's History of New York (London: T. Palser, 1830) all engraved after Steeden's own design.
    - "Governor Stuyvesant Resolves to Defend his Horse" (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
    - "Dedrick Knickerbocker Chiding his Landlady for settling his room to rights" (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
    - "Squatters Arriving at a Fresh Settlement" (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
    - "Van Twiller and Council Met in Debate" (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
    - "The renowned Van Corlear, the Dutch Trumpeter" (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
    - "The Four Great Dutch Characters, Van Zant, Hardenbrock, Ten Broeken, and Van Courtland" (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
    - "Negro Servant Relating Tales to the Settlers" (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
    - "Dutch Cobbler Haranguing the Mob" (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
    - "Farm Yard Melody, or the Dutch Settler's Glory" (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
  - Stokes, Caroline Phelps (1854-1909)
    - [Residence of Anson Greene Phelps, East River and 30th], undated (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
  - Sturges, Dwight Case (1874-1940)
    - #1 Broadway, after 1921 (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
  - Sumner, H. F. & Co.
    - "Eleanor", 1833 (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
      hand-colored, drawn by J. Penniman
    - "The Love Letter", 1833 (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
      drawn by J. Penniman
  - Szanto, Lajos (Louis) (1889-1965)
    - News boys, Wall Street, ca. 1935 (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box S, Folder unknown container)
      etching and drypoint
  - Thienny?, G. A.
    - [Snow scene, with bridge over creek], undated (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box T, Folder unknown container)
  - Tittle, Walter Ernest (1883-1966)
    - Manhattan Minarets, undated (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box T, Folder unknown container)
  - Trowbridge, Vaughan (1869-1945)
    - [London Terrace], undated (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box T, Folder unknown container)
      color etching
  - Trueblood, Emily (b. 1942)
    - City Towers (2/50), 1994 (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box T, Folder unknown container)
      linocut
    - Night Tower(31/50), 2000 (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box T, Folder unknown container)
    - Rooftop View 1 (16/50), 2000 (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box T, Folder unknown container)
      woodcut
    - World Trade View (31/50), 1995 (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box T, Folder unknown container)
  - Vanderhook, ?
    - St. John the Divine, undated (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box V, Folder unknown container)
  - Van Notti, Henry (1878-1962)
    - Barclay St., New York, [1915] (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box V, Folder unknown container)
    - New and Old New York, [1910] (Offsite-box Box S-V, Box V, Folder unknown container)
  - Walcot, William (1874-1943)
    - Brooklyn Bridge, [1920] (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
  - Walker, Steven (b. 1955)
    - Sunset Skyline, 1999 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
  - Wall, Bernhardt (1872-1956)
    - Italian Church on Minetta Lane, 1918 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Ten Etchings of Greenwich Village Landmarks in the War Year of 1918, 1947 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
      bound booklet
  - Wallace, William H.
    - "Along the Hackensack", undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Ann Street, corner Theatre Alley, undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Bradburns Bookstall, undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "Clean-Drinking Manor House, Maryland", undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - The Burdell House at 31 Bond Street, undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Fog Under Bridge Tower, 1882 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Fulton Street [(Brooklyn) Between Johnson and Myrtle Ave East Side], 1845 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - [Grape Vine Inn; Last of the Shades], undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Harlem River in 1870 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
      2 copies, different sizes
    - Middle Dutch Reform Church (proof), 1882 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Middle Dutch Reform Church (final), 1882 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Middle Dutch Reform Church (2nd state), 1882 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - [New York from Staten Island (?)], 1890 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Old New York, undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "Old School house, Tuckahoe Rd., Mt. Vernon", 1881 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - [Post Office at Cedar and Nassau Streets], 1888 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "Prison of Major Andre", undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - [Prospect Park - Apple Trees], undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "Trees at Demorest", undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
  - Waller, Frank (1842-1923)
    - [Museum interior], 1893 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
  - Ward, Caleb
    - "View of the Spot where Gen. Hamilton fell at Weehawk [with a View of New York]", 1830 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
      Hand-colored aquatint after Jacob C. Ward, date depicted 1806.
  - Ward, Lynd (1905-1985)
    - Under the El, undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
  - Werger, Art (b.1955)
    - Attraction, 2003 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
      mezzotint
    - Daybreak (56/75), 1997 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Early Thaw (72/75), 1996 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
  - Whistler, James Abbott McNeill (1834-1903)
    "Twelve Etchings from Nature," printed in Paris, published in London by James A. Whistler, 1858, in original wrapper
    - "Liverdun" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Folder unknown container)
    - "La Retameuse" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "En Plein Soleil" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "The Unsafe Tenement" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "La Mere Gerard" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "Street at Saverne" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "Little Arthur" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "La Vielle aux Loques" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "Annie" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "La Marchande de Moutarde" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "Fumette" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "The Kitchen" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
  - White, Charles Henry (1878-1918)
    - Bit of Bleecker St. (3/10), 1903 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Bleecker St. Gables, N.Y., 1903 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Boiler Works [David M. Nichols Boiler Works], 1902 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box Q, Folder unknown container)
    - East River Bridge II, 1903 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Five Points, N.Y., undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Hudson Street (16/25), undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Mulberry Bend, N.Y., 1903 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Old Warf II, Third State, undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - [Shipsmith and blacksmith shop], undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Folder unknown container)
    - The Tenement, Third State, 1903 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Thompson Street Inn, Fifth State, undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
  - Whitefield, Edwin (1816-1892)
    - "Lobelia Syphilitica", undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
      hand-colored lithograph by Lewis & Brown, New York, after drawings by Whitefield, illustration from Emma C. Embury's American Wild Flowers in Their Native Haunts (New York: D. Appleton & Co., 1845)
  - Wilbur, Lawrence Nelson (1897-1988)
    - Along the Docks (5/50), [1945] (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
      after his watercolor
    - The East River, 1946 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Manhattan Mountains, 1938 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Old Brownstones - New York (16/50), 1923 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Peck's Slip - N.Y.C. (proof), 1938 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - September- Central Park (32/50), undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - The Spire [Empire State Building] (4/100), undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Under the Bridge (6/27), 1988 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - [Produce stands] (7/75), 1976 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - [Produce stands] (9/75), 1976 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
  - Wolchonok, Louis (1898-1973)
    - Bridge, Sheepshead Bay (71/150), undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Fort Lee Ferry (28/150), undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Fourteenth Street, undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Hellgate Bridge (1/150), undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - [New York Telephone and Telegraph Building] (25/150), undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - [Saint Paul's], undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - [Sheepshead Bay] (40/150), undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - [Spring in Central Park], undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - [Street Construction, New York] (7/150), undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - Subway Construction at 8th Ave. and 116th St., 1926 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - [Riverside Park with bridge] (1st proof, 2nd state), undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - [Weber Coal Company], undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
      [Attributed]
    - [Woolworth Building], undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
  - Wolf, Henry (1852-1916)
    - [Woman with two children], undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
      Inscribed to Samuel Shaw from Abbott Handerson Thayer (1849-1921)
  - Woodruff, Hale (1900-1980)
    - "African Headdress" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "By Parties Unknown" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "Coming Home" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "Giddap" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "Old Church" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "Relics" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "Sunday Promenade" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
    - "Trusty on a Mule" (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
      Portfolio, 156 of 300, all linocuts dating from 1931-1940, printed in 1996
  - Woodcut Society, wood engravings published by
    - Buckland-Wright, John, 1897-1954, "The Forest Pool, 1939 (Offsite-box Woodcut Society, Folder unknown container)
    - Cheffetz, Asa, 1896-1965, "Midsummer Vermont", 1936 (Offsite-box Woodcut Society, Folder unknown container)
    - Cheffetz, Asa, 1896-1965, "Down Montgomery Way (Vermont)", 1940 (Offsite-box Woodcut Society, Folder unknown container)
    - Cook, Howard Norton, 1901-1980, "Eagle Dance", 1942 (Offsite-box Woodcut Society, Folder unknown container)
    - Landacre, Paul, 1893-1963, "Black Stallion, undated (Offsite-box Woodcut Society, Folder unknown container)
    - Lathrop, Dorothy P. "Kou Hsiung", 1944 (Offsite-box Woodcut Society, Folder unknown container)
    - Leighton, Clare, b. 1899, "Winnowers Majorca", 1939 (Offsite-box Woodcut Society, Folder unknown container)
    - Lindsay, Lionel, b. 1874, "Repose", 1938 (Offsite-box Woodcut Society, Folder unknown container)
  - Wortsman, Harold
    - "A new form of skywriting", undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
  - Wyllie, William L. (1851-1931)
    - [Ship in New York Harbor, with tugboats], ca. 1895-1903 (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box W, Folder unknown container)
  - Zabriskie, George A. (1868-1954)
    - Ten untitled prints, undated (Offsite-box Box W-Z, Box Z, Folder unknown container)
- Series II: Prints 16 x 20" to 30 x 40"
  Series II. Prints 16 x 20" to 30 x 40," is also filed by artist or printmaker's surname. The prints are are housed in drawers in flat files. This series contains many important eighteenth-century prints, particularly views of New York City.
  Three of Karl Akrell's engravings after Axel Leonhard Klinckowstrom are from Klinckowstrom's Atlas, which was published in Sweden in 1824. A complete copy of this early work is also held by the Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections. The view of City Hall is notable for the pigs shown prominently in the foreground.
  Pierre Charles Canot, a French engraver working in London, engraved these two views of New York City after drawings by Thomas Howdell, a member of the Royal Artillery of the British Army. They were published in London in around 1768 as part of Scenographia America, a collection of twenty-eight views of American cities. The view from the south-east includes one of the first impressions of King's College (now Columbia University).
  Amos Doolittle's son A. B. Doolittle's engraving of Yale College is included in this series.
  The French lithographing firm of Engelmann Pére et Fils (Godefroy Engelmann, principal) completed six scenes of Vues de L'Amerique du Nord; all six were printed as the basis for wallpaper blocks. Complete sets are rare; the Society has three. The view of New York includes African Americans.
  The etching by Paul Fourdrinier is the earliest plan of Savannah known to exist. The first settlers came in 1733, and the print was issued the next year.
  Ambroise-Louis Garneray, a French artist and engraver, issued a series of travel views in the early eighteenth century, Vues des coites de France dans l'Ocean et dans la Mediteranee. The fifth volume, Voyage Maritime, featured views of great port cities, including several American ports. Garneray never visited America but copied the views of other artists.
  Thomas Johnston's view of the battle at Lake George is from the French and Indian War.
  Paul Sandby 1725-1809 is considered the founder of the watercolor movement in England, and was also the first English artist to use the aquatint process. The views by and after Sandby here were originally sketches by the colonial Massachusetts Governor Thomas Pownall. Sandby painted each view, and engraved several of them. The six prints here were first published in 1761 under the title of Six Remarkable Views in the Provinces of New-York, New-Jersey, and Pennsylvania, in North America, and were later reissued as part of Scenographia Americana, mentioned above, in 1768.
  Prints are filed alphabetically by artist or printmaker's surname.
  - Akrell, Carl Frederik (1779-1868)
    After Axel Leonhard Klinckowstrom (1775-1837).
    - "Broadway -Gatan Och Radhuset I New York" [Broadway and City Hall], 1819 (Folder FF-A)
    - "New Yorks Hamn Och Redd Fran Brooklyn Pa Long Island" [New York Harbor from Brooklyn], 1820 (Folder FF-A)
      aquatint, 2 copies
    - "Chancellor Livingston", [1819] (Folder FF-A)
      plan of boat
    - "Atlas" title page, 1824 (Folder FF-A)
  - Barlow, Lou (1908-2011)
    - "Cafe", linocut, artist's proof, ca. 1935 (Folder FF-B)
    - "Dialogue," color linocut, impression 7 of 14, 1990 (Folder FF-B)
    - "The Rescue", color linocut, artist's proof, ca.1991 (Folder FF-B)
    - "The Sculptor", linocut, artist's proof, 1994 (Folder FF-B)
    - "Self Portrait", linocut, artist's proof, 2003 (Folder FF-B)
    - "Symphony Orchestra", linocut, artist's proof, 1988 (Folder FF-B)
  - Beamley, William Jean
    - Chambers Street, New York City, 1913 (Folder FF-B)
      Photomechanical reproduction, color
  - Behnken, William (b.1943)
    - Bronx Crossing, 1991 (Folder FF-B)
  - Bosman, Richard (b. 1944)
    - [Brooklyn Bridge], undated (Folder FF-B)
  - Briem, Gottlob L. (1899-1972)
    - The Chrysler Building, New York City, N.Y., undated (Folder FF-B)
  - Brosen, Frederick (b. 1954)
    - [Brooklyn Bridge], 1992 (Folder FF-B)
  - Brown, Goerge Loring (1814-1889)
    - [New York City from across river], 1861 (Folder FF-B)
      Finished by Alexander Hay Ritchie (1822-1895). Published by George Ward Nichols, New York
  - Bry, Edith (1898-1991)
    - "Sold", undated (Folder FF-B)
      lithograph, impression 9 of 20
      See also: Series I
  - Canot, Pierre-Charles (1710-1777)
    after Thomas Howdell.
    - "A South East View of the City of New York in North America", [1768] (Folder FF-C)
      published by T. Jefferys, London
    - "A South West View of the City of New York in North America", [1768] (Folder FF-C)
  - Cartwright, T.
    After a drawing by George Beck (ca. 1748-1812).